Guide to the Robert A. M. Stern Architects Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional and personal records, 1980-1989; Accession 2011-M-021
  - Public events, 1980-1989
    - Television, 1980-1986
      - General appearances [firm barcode 40010930], 1980-1982 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
      - Pride of Place, 1986
        - Correspondence [firm barcode 40010930], 1983-1986 (Box 21, Folder 3-6)
        - Fees/reimbursables [firm barcode 40010930], 1984 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - General [firm barcode 40010930], 1986 (Box 21, Folder 8)
        - Images -- Episodes 1-8 and promotional kit [firm barcode 40010930], 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 9-17)
        - Legal agreements [firm barcode 40010930], 1985 (Box 21, Folder 18)
        - Publicity [firm barcode 40010930], 1986 (Box 21, Folder 19-27)
        - Related programs [firm barcode 40010931], 1980-1987 (Box 22, Folder 1-10)
        - Research, 1980-1985
          - Photocopies of scouting trip photographs, California-Oklahoma [firm barcode 40010931], 1980-1985 (Box 22, Folder 11-25)
          - Photocopies of scouting trip photographs, Pennsylvania-Washington, DC [firm barcode 40010932], 1980-1985 (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
          - Production notes, 1980-1985
            - Episodes 1A-1N [firm barcode 40010932], 1980-1985 (Box 23, Folder 6-16)
            - Episodes 2A-2N [firm barcode 40010932], 1980-1985 (Box 23, Folder 17-27)
            - Episodes 3B-3J [firm barcode 40010932], 1980-1985 (Box 23, Folder 28-35)
            - Episodes 4A-4L [firm barcode 40010933], 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 1-12)
            - Episodes 5A-5L [firm barcode 40010933], 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 13-20)
            - Episodes 6A-6L [firm barcode 40010933], 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 21-31)
            - Episodes 7A-7M [firm barcode 40010933], 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 32-38)
            - Episodes 8E-8M and episode guide [firm barcode 40010933], 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 39-45)
        - Schedules [firm barcode 40010933], 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 46-47)
        - Schedules [firm barcode 40010934], 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
        - Transcripts [firm barcode 40010934], 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 3-11)
        - Writings, 1980-1985
          - Drafts, notes, and outlines [firm barcode 40010934], 1980-1985 (Box 25, Folder 12-13)
          - Episode synopses [firm barcode 40010934], 1983 (Box 25, Folder 14)
          - Master script, episodes 1-8 [firm barcode 40010934], 1985 (Box 25, Folder 15-22)
          - Post-production scripts, episodes 1-8 [firm barcode 40010934], 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 23-30)
          - Project proposal [firm barcode 40010934], 1984 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Student work: Yale thesis review, 1962; 1 (Box 37)
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Digital master copy, 1
  - Student work: Yale thesis review Use copy, 1962; 1 (Box 37U1–37U2)
  - Teaching, 1980-1989
    - 1980-1984 [firm barcode 40010935] (Box 26, Folder 1-38)
    - 1984-1987 [firm barcode 40010936] (Box 27, Folder 1-30)
    - 1988-1989 [firm barcode 40010937] (Box 28, Folder 1-12)
  - Writings, 1980-1989
    - 1980
      - Architectural Design -- "Modern Architecture After Modernism" [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Architectural Design Profile -- "Chicago Tribune Tower" [firm barcode 40010937] (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Architectural Design Profile -- "Classicism in Context" [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Book proposal -- Making Metropolis [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Design Quarterly -- "Subway Suburb, 1976-80" [firm barcode 40010937] (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - GA Document -- "Notes on American Architecture in the Waning of the Petroleum Era" [firm barcode 40010937] (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Harvard Architecture Review -- "The Doubles of Post-Modern" [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - New York -- "Shades of Fred and Ginger" [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Pantheon Books -- The Architect's Eye [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Unpublished articles [firm barcode 40010937], 1980 (Box 28, Folder 22-24)
    - 1981
      - A+U extra edition -- American Architecture [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 25-29)
      - "Apropos 1900: New York and the Metropolitan Ideal" [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - Architectural Design monograph -- Robert Stern [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - "Architecture, History, and Historiography at the End of the Modernist Era" [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - "Discontinuity and Continuity in Modern Architecture: Modernism and Post-Modernism" [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - "Human Scale at the End of the Age of Modernism" [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 34)
      - Macmillan Encyclopedia of Architects -- "George Howe" [firm barcode 40010937], 1981 (Box 28, Folder 35)
      - "Toward a Modern Architecture After Modernism" [firm barcode 40010938], 1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Skyline -- "Giedion's Ghost" [firm barcode 40010938], 1981 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Skyline -- "Setting the Stage: Herts & Tallant" [firm barcode 40010938], 1981 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Unpublished article for House Beautiful -- "Modern Architecture and the Modern House" [firm barcode 40010938], 1981 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Yale Seminars in Architecture -- "Notes on Post-Modernism" [firm barcode 40010938], 1981 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - 1982
      - A+U extra edition -- Robert A. M. Stern [firm barcode 40010938] (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Cooper-Hewitt Museum -- "Toward an Urban Suburbia, Once Again" [firm barcode 40010938], 1982 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - East Hampton's Heritage -- "One Hundred Years of Resort Architecture in East Hampton: The Power of the Provincial" [firm barcode 40010938], 1978-1983 (Box 29, Folder 8-19)
      - Progressive Architecture -- "International Style: Immediate Effects" [firm barcode 40010938], 1982 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - 1983
      - Architectural History Foundation -- Forward to Bertram Grosvenor Goodhue [firm barcode 40010939], 1983 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Architectural History Foundation -- Forward to The Almighty Wall: The Architecture of Henry Vaughn [firm barcode 40010939], 1983 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Hype, Steven M. L. Aronson [firm barcode 40010939], 1983 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - RAMSA office brochure [firm barcode 40010939], 1983 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - 1984
      - "After the Modern Period" [firm barcode 40010939], 1984 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - AIA Gold Medal -- "Philip Cortelyou Johnson" [firm barcode 40010939], 1984 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Architectural Digest -- "Guest Speaker: Robert A. M. Stern on Avoiding the Architectural Zoo" [firm barcode 40010939], 1984 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Art Institute of Chicago -- "Commentary on Chicago and New York" [firm barcode 40010939], 1984 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Precis -- "On Style, Classicism, and Pedagogy" [firm barcode 40010939], 1984 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Unpublished piece for National Building Museum -- Paul Cret assessment [firm barcode 40010939], 1984 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - 1985
      - A+U: Architecture and Urbanism -- "Four Towers" [firm barcode 40010939], 1985 (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - International Design Yearbook -- Introduction [firm barcode 40010939], 1985 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - 1986
      - Architectural Digest -- "Guest Speaker: Robert A. M. Stern: Designing the American Dream" [firm barcode 40010939], 1986 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Architecture -- letter to the editor [firm barcode 40010939], 1986 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Atlanta real estate brochure -- blurb [firm barcode 40010939], 1986 (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Charles Moore: Buildings and Projects 1949-1986 -- "Charles Moore: The Architect Running in Place" [firm barcode 40010939] (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - Houses of the Hamptons -- "Robert A. M. Stern" [firm barcode 40010939], 1986 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Monograph introduction -- "Modern Traditionalism" [firm barcode 40010939], 1986 (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - New York -- "New York in the Year 2000" [firm barcode 40010939], 1986 (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - Pride of Place book material [firm barcode 40010939], 1983-1986 (Box 30, Folder 20-32)
    - 1987
      - Architectural Digest -- "Lighting: Ten Leading Architects" [firm barcode 40010939], 1987 (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - Architectural Digest -- "Travel Notes: An Architect's Impressions of France" [firm barcode 40010939], 1987 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Arquitectura -- "America and the Single-Family Home" [firm barcode 40010939], 1987 (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Lighting Dimensions -- "From the 'Stanford White of Our Time'" [firm barcode 40010939], 1987 (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - Unpublished article for Metamorfosi [firm barcode 40010939], 1987 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - 1988
      - 42nd Street Exhibition -- catalog essay [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Akademie der Wissenschaften competition [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Architectural Design -- "Design as Emulation" [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Architectural Digest -- "Furniture: Seven Leading Architects[...]" [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Architecture -- "New Yorkers on New York" [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Design Journal -- "An Architect Should Recall and Invent" [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Modern Classicism, 1986-1990
        - Correspondence [firm barcode 40010940], 1986-1988 (Box 31, Folder 7-8)
        - Illustrations [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 9-15)
        - Research: Adam, Robert through Garay, Miguel [firm barcode 40010940], 1988 (Box 31, Folder 16-28)
        - Research: General through Krier, Robert [firm barcode 40010941], 1988 (Box 32, Folder 1-20)
        - Research: Langlois, Christian through Stern, Robert A. M. [firm barcode 40010942], 1988 (Box 33, Folder 1-23)
        - Research: Stirling, James through Venturi, Robert [firm barcode 40010943], 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1-8)
        - Writing [firm barcode 40010943], 1988 (Box 34, Folder 9-17)
      - On Diseno -- "Urbanismo Clasico" [firm barcode 40010944], 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Tahara, Keiichi foreword -- "Transatlantic Crossings" [firm barcode 40010944], 1988 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Unpublished article for Modulus -- "Modernism in Perspective [firm barcode 40010944], 1988 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Unpublished article for Modulus -- "Placing Norman Rockwell" [firm barcode 40010944], 1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 1989
      - Architectural Digest -- "Robert A.M. Stern: An Architect's Impressions of Spain" [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Architectural Digest -- "Stanley Tigerman" [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Architecture -- "Architecture in the 1980s" [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Architecture of the American Summer -- Foreword [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Architektura -- "On Contextual Design" [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Glamour, Glitz and Sparkle: The Deco Theatres of John Eberson -- Prologue [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Sublime Architecture: Esquisses/Sketches -- Introduction [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Metropolis -- "Design of the Eighties" [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - New York City Access -- "Best of New York" [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Newport Houses -- Introduction [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Perspecta: The First Twenty-Five -- Introduction [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Unpublished "Op-Ed" piece on McCarren Park Pool [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Wallace Neff -- Introduction [firm barcode 40010944], 1989 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Undated
      - Metropolitan Suburb book, Circa 1983
        - Correspondence [firm barcode 40010944], Circa 1983 (Box 35, Folder 18)
        - Drafts [firm barcode 40010944], Circa 1983 (Box 35, Folder 19-22)
        - Final manuscript [firm barcode 40010944], Circa 1983 (Box 35, Folder 23)
        - Grant applications [firm barcode 40010944], Circa 1983 (Box 35, Folder 24)
      - Vincent Scully festschrift, 1979-1990
        - Correspondence [firm barcode 40010945], 1979-1989 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
        - Notes and status updates [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 3)
        - RAMS essay
          - Drafts [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 4)
          - Final manuscript [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 5)
          - Research [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
        - Submissions
          - Brooks, Turner [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 8)
          - de Bretteville, Peter [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 9)
          - Duany and Plater-Zyberk [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 10)
          - Hewitt, Mark A. [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 11)
          - Jarrett, James R. [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 12)
          - Kliment and Halsband [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 13)
          - Pasanella and Klein [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 14)
          - Rose, Peter [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 15)
          - Scully, Daniel V. [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 16)
          - Studio di Architettura [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 17)
          - Tigerman, Stanley [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 18)
          - Venturi, Robert [firm barcode 40010945], Circa 1989 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Paul Rudolph's review of Stern's small office building (Box 38)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
- Vincent Scully: Yale University, interviews with Robert A. M. Stern, 2008-2009; Accession 2011-M-080
  The records consist of DVDs and transcripts of interviews with Robert A.M. Stern discussing Vincent Scully for a production by the Checkerboard Film Foundation. The finished project, Vincent Scully: An Art Historian Among Among Architects, is available on DVD.
  - Interviews
    - Art and Architecture building, tape 301
      - Use Copy, 2008 December 9; 1 (Box 1U)
    - Tape 702
      - Use Copy, 2009 November 12; 1 (Box 2U)
    - Tape 703
      - Use Copy, 2009 November 12; 1 (Box 3U)
  - Transcripts
    - Art and Architecture building, tape 301, 2008 December 9 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Tape 702, 2009 November 12 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Tape 703, 2009 November 12 (Box 4, Folder 3)